[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
This next section will talk about how to pick that threshold split,
سنتحدث في هذا القسم عن كيفية اختيار الحد لتقسيم،
H equals 38 over income with 60,000 for continuous valued features.
H تساوي 36 على الدخل بقيمة 60000 للحصول على ميزات ذات قيمة مستمرة.
We're going to make this an optional session.
سنعتبر هذه الجلسة اختيارية.
Its not super complicated but is that a little bit laborious?
هذا لا يعني أنها غاية في التعقيد بل شاقة إلى حد ما؟
So, if you're interested, definitely take a deep dive, but for
فإذا كنت مهتمًا، يمكنك بالتأكيد التعمق في هذا المجال،
those who want to skip it, it's totally okay.
أما للذين يرغبون في تخطيها، فلا مشكلة على الإطلاق.
So the goal here is to ask, if I decide to split, on say income,
إذاً، الهدف هنا هو أن تسأل، إذا قررت أن أقسم، على سبيل المثال الدخل،
how do I choose the splitting point, p star, that we won't separate,
كيف أختار نقطة التقسيم p star، والتي لن تنطبق عليها عملية الفصل،
now case of 60,000, but we want to split the left and right side of the tree.
في حالة 60000، فنحن نريد تقسيم الجانب الأيسر والأيمن من التسلسل.
Now, this infinite many values that t
فهناك العديد من القيم اللانهائية التي قد تتعامل معها t star
star could take, it could be $60,000, $50,999.99, and if this
قد تكون 60000$ أو 50999.99$، وإذا كانت بالفعل مستمرة،
is truly continuous it could go to infinite remaining decimal places.
فقد تمتد للنقاط العشرية اللانهائية المتبقية.
The question is do we need to consider all of those.
والسؤال هو، هل نحتاج إلى النظر في كل ذلك؟
And do all those decimal places really effect the quality of our decision tree?
وهل تؤثر كل هذه النقاط العشرية على جودة تسلسل القرارات؟
Now if you think about it and
إذا فكرت في الأمر
if you look at the values that income can take on the data so
إذا نظرت إلى القيم التي قد يحتوي عليها الدخل في البيانات
actual of income you'll see that if you take two points of say VA, and VB.
فسترى أن الدخل الفعلي يمكن استنباطه من نقطتين ولنفترض أنهما VA و VB.
Let's say 60,000, and 65,000.
ولنفترض أن قيمة كليهما 60000 و 65000.
If there are no points in between, whether the split is at 61,000, 62,000, 63,000,
وإذا لم تكن هناك أي نقاط بينهما، سواء كان التقسيم 61000 أو 62000 أو 63000،
64,000, you're still going to have the same classification error.
أو 64000، فستتلقى نفس الخطأ في التصنيف باستمرار.
The points on the left of that split always going to be the same,
وستكون النقاط على يسار هذا الانقسام دائمًا كما هي،
the points on the right of the split cannot be the same.
أما النقاط على اليمين فستكون بمقادير مختلفة.
So all I have to do,
وكل ما يمكنني فعله هو،
is consider the middle point, between any of the data points that we have, and
النظر في نقطة الوسط، بين أي من نقاط البيانات التي لدينا
just consider those to be the possible splits for my data.
واعتبارها كنقطة تقسيم لبياناتي.
And that's exactly what we're going to do.
وهذا بالضبط ما سنفعله.
Let's now close the section by walking through the algorithm for
دعونا ننهِ هذا القسم باتباع خوارزمية
picking the best splitting point, for a particular feature.
انتقاء نقطة التقسيم الفضلى للميزات المحددة.
So let's say that I'm considering splitting, on the feature here, hj,
لنفترض أنني أفكر في التقسيم، على الميزة هنا، hj،
which might be in our case, income, and, what I can do is go through all my data,
والتي قد تتمثل في الدخل، في تلك الحالة، ما يمكنني فعله هو مراجعة جميع بياناتي،
so the column of values of the income might take, and sort them.
حتى يأخذها عمود قيم الدخل، ليقوم بفرزها بعد ذلك.
Such that V1 is the lowest income, V2 is the next lowest and
بحيث يكون V1 هو أدنى دخل، و V2 هو الأدنى التالي
VN is the highest income.
و VN هو أعلى دخل.
And all I need to consider is the splitting points right in between V1 and
وكل ما أحتاج أخذه في الاعتبار هي النقاط المقسمة بين V1 و V2
V2, V2 and V3 and so on.
وبين V2 و V3 وهكذا.
So I walk from i = 1 though N-1 and then consider splitting point ti,
لذلك أراجع من i = 1 إلى N-1 ثم أقسم النقطة ti،
which is the midpoint between Vi and Vi+1, and I ask what is the classification
وهي نقطة الوسط بين Vi و Vi + 1 ، ثم أحاول معرفة خطأ التصنيف
error if I were to build a decision tree, a decision stump in this case,
إذا كنت أحاول إنشاء تسلسل قرارات، أو في تلك الحالة؛ فرع قرارات،
that splits xj on ti, on greater than ti and less than ti?
الذي يقسم xj على ti في الحالات الأكبر من ti ومثيلتها الأصغر من ti.
So greater than 60,000 and lower than 60,000.
أو بمعنى آخر أكبر من 60000 وأقل من 60000.
And then we'll pick.
وبعد ذلك ننتقي
t star, to be the split that leads to decision stump,
t star لتكون هي نقطة التقسيم التي توصلنا إلى فرع للقرارات،
with the lowest classification error.
بأقل خطأ في التصنيف.
And that's it.
وهذا كل ما في الأمر.
Pretty simple algorithm, pretty easy to take from here.
خوارزمية بسيطة تجعل من السهل البناء عليها.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]